Earlier, we discussed a basic optimization problem.
之前我们讨论了一种基本优化问题
It's possible for optimization problems to have an additional wrinkle.
优化问题存在其他约束条件
Constraints can be placed on the problem
对问题设定约束条件
to limit the region where you look for a solution.
会限定解的区间
In other words, you try to find the smallest value of
换句话说 要寻找的
the function that also satisfies the constraints.
还满足约束条件函数最小解
Let's discuss how to solve an optimization problem with constraints.
下面讲解如何在有约束条件下求解的优化问题
First, let's clarify some terminology.
先介绍几个术语
The function we are trying to optimize is called the objective or cost function.
我们要优化的函数称为目标或成本函数
The variable we are trying to optimize,
我们要优化的变量
which in portfolio optimization is the vector
在投资组合优化中是
of weights on the various assets in the portfolio,
投资组合中各个资产的权重向量
is called the optimization variable.
称为优化变量
Then we may have various constraints.
然后可能存在各种约束条件
The constraints can take the form of inequality or equality conditions.
约束条件可以是不等式或等式条件
If there are no constraints,
如果没有约束条件
we say the problem is unconstrained.
那么问题不受约束
If the objective function is x minus one squared plus one
如果目标函数为 (x-1)^2+1
and we apply the constraint that x must be less than or equal to zero,
约束条件为 x 必须小于等于 0
then the new minimum value is two because this is
那么新的最小值为 2
the smallest value of the function that also satisfies the constraint.
因为这个函数最小值也满足约束条件
A vector x is called optimal or a solution of the problem if it has
如果向量 x 在满足约束条件的所有向量中具有最小目标值
the smallest objective value among all vectors that satisfy the constraints.
那么 x 是问题的最优值或解
The set of points for which the objective and
定义目标和所有约束函数的点集合
all the constraint functions are defined is called the domain of the problem.
称为问题的定义域
A point in the domain is said to be feasible if it satisfies all the constraints.
如果定义域的点满足所有约束条件 则该点是可行的
The problem is feasible if there exists at least one feasible point,
如果至少存在一个可行点 那么问题是可行的
and it is infeasible otherwise.
否则是不可行的
If there are feasible points for which the objective function reaches negative infinity,
如果有使目标函数达到负无穷的可行点
we say the problem is unbounded below.
那么该问题是下方无界问题
This is the case for the function f of x equals
没有约束条件的 f(x) = -ln(x)
the negative natural log of x with no constraints.
就属于下方无界问题
A general optimization problem can be very difficult to solve.
一般的优化问题可能很难求解
You can have functions of many variables and
函数可能有很多变量
the objective function and constraints can be very complicated.
目标函数和约束条件可能很复杂
So, instead of thinking about how to solve all types of optimization problems,
我们将只思考如何求解特定类型的优化问题
let's just think about how to solve certain types.
而不去思考如何求解所有类型的优化问题
It turns out that there are well developed methods to solve some sub-types of problems,
实际上 某些问题有成熟的求解方法
and they will be of great help to us as we try to optimize our portfolios.
这些方法对于优化投资组合来说很有用
It turns out that a very important type of optimization problem is one for which
有一类优化问题很重要
the objective function and inequality constraints are convex.
这类问题的目标函数和不等式约束条件是凸函数
What does that mean? Well, it's actually very intuitive.
这是什么意思实际上含义很直观
A convex function curves upward everywhere.
凸函数在所有位置的曲线都向上弯曲
Any straight line you draw between two points
在函数上的任何两点之间的连线
on the function has to lie above the function.
都位于函数上方
So, this wiggly function would not be convex.
所以这个扭动的函数不是凸函数
An important property of a convex optimization problem is that it only has one minimum.
凸优化问题的一个重要特性是它只有一个最小值
So, if you find a local minimum,
如果你找到局部最小值了
you know it is the globally optimal value over the whole feasible region.
那么它就是整个可行区域内的全局最优值
This is actually hugely helpful.
这个特性很有用
When the objective function and inequality constraints are convex and
如果目标函数和不等式约束条件是凸函数
the equality constraints have the form f of x equals a times x plus b,
并且等式约束条件是 f(x)=a^T * x + b
the optimization problem is called a convex optimization problem.
那么这个优化问题称为凸优化问题
If you find a local optimum for this problem,
如果你找到这种问题的局部最优解
you know it is a global optimum.
那么它就是全局最优解
There are well developed techniques for solving these problems,
这些问题有一些很成熟的求解方法
and the set of problems we deal with during
在优化投资组合过程中遇到的问题
portfolio optimization will generally be of this type.
通常都是这类问题